A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, F-L FA392
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Gregg, Alan, 1.97 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 5 microfilm boxes (35mm)
  - 1931, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 107 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 419)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg studies present day needs in medical education and sciences to develop programs with medical schools to improve facilities and research. Gregg is now the Director of Medical Sciences of the Rockefeller Foundation after Richard Pearce died the previous year. In 1931, funding and creation of new programs in psychiatry at major American medical universities begins.
  - Exhibit, 1931; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957)
    Includes: "Sir William Hardy's Impressions of Vanderbilt Medical School," "AG Interview with Dr. William H. Park," "AG Interview with Dr. C. C. Bass, Dean Tulane University Medical School," "Visit to University of Pennsylvania in Connection with Request for Aid in Neurology," "Visit to Research Laboratory at Lankenau Hospital, Philadelphia," "Memorandum regarding request of President Hutchins of Chicago for building equipment and endowment for work of Dr. Edmund Jacobson", and "Report of Interview with M. C. Winternitz".
    Exhibitions
  - Index, 1932; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 489, Box 181)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1932 diary
    Medical education; indexes (reference sources)
  - 1932, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 163 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 526)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg studies present day needs in medical education and sciences to develop programs with medical schools to improve facilities and research. Gregg tours the United States to visit various hospitals, laboratories and medical facilities. He attends the Committee on the Costs of Medical Care Meeting.
    Medicine -- Research; Medicine; Medical education; Hygiene; Psychiatry; Diaries
  - Index, 1933; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 692, Box 181)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1933 diary
  - 1933, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 160 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 697)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg studies present day needs in medical education and sciences to develop programs with medical schools to improve facilities and research. Harvard Medical School and Massachusetts General Hospital program in psychiatry is detailed, a Conference on Program in Aid of Exiled Germans is attended and a trip to Toronto is taken.
    Diaries; Canada; Psychiatry; Physiology; Pediatrics; United States; Public health; Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978); Peking Union Medical College
  - Index, 1934; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 879, Box 181)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1934 diary
    United States; Medical education; indexes (reference sources)
  - 1934, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 884)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg studies present day needs in medical education and sciences to develop programs with medical schools to improve facilities and research. The Chicago Area Project studying juvenile delinquency is detailed. Gregg travels around Europe surveying facets of psychiatry. The diary includes trustee and staff conferences notes.
    United States; England; Netherlands; Diaries
  - Index, 1935; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 1,050)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1935 diary
    Diaries; Medical education; United States
  - 1935, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 110 pages (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 1,054, Box 181)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg studies present day needs in medical education and sciences to develop programs with medical schools to improve facilities and research.
    United States; Diaries; Nervous system; Psychiatry; Psychobiology
  - Index, 1936; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 181, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 1)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1936 diary
    United States; Canada; indexes (reference sources); Medical education
  - 1936, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 110 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 6)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg travels around the United States and Canada assessing RF Medical Sciences research. He attends RF Officer Conferences. The diary also contains discussions about how to help deposed German scholars.
    Medicine, Preventive; Human genetics; Psychiatry; Neurology; Canada; Diaries; Child psychiatry; United States; Public health
  - Index, 1937; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 181, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 116)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1937 diary
  - 1937, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 145 pages (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 121, Box 182)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg travels around the United States, Canada and Western Europe.
    Russia; Scotland; Psychiatry; Public health; Diaries; Child psychiatry; Germany; France; Neurology; Human genetics; Prevention and health; Poland; United States; Canada; Switzerland; Peking Union Medical College; Planck, Max (1858-1947); Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
  - Index, 1938; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 266, Box 182)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1938 diary
  - 1938, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 165 pages (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 271, Box 182)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. In 1938, Medical Sciences begins to focus its energy on establishing and maintaining university departments of psychiatry, expanding teaching and research in psychiatry and neurology, and education the public in mental hygiene. Gregg attends the Conference on Industrial Psychology and Milbank Conference. The diary includes "Memo and Conference Minutes: 1 February 1937- 19 December 1938.
    Public health; Psychiatry; Population; Neurology; Medicine, Preventive; Human genetics; Genetics; Endocrinology; Diaries; Child psychiatry; Biochemistry; United States; Peking Union Medical College
  - Index, 1939; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 182, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 436)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1939 diary
  - 1939, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 154 pages (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 440, Box 182)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. There is a Staff Conference on the Effect of Declaration of War on European Programs and Plans. Includes "Staff Conference: 7 March- 16 November 1939."
    World War II; United States; Endocrinology; Neurology; Genetics; Neurophysiology; Human genetics; Population; Medicine, Preventive; Psychiatry; Public health; Biochemistry; Canada; Child psychiatry; Diaries; Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978); Peking Union Medical College
  - Index, 1940; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 182, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 595)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1940 diary
  - 1940, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 193 pages (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 600, Box 182)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg tours Western Europe. Includes "Staff Conference: 21 May- 10 December 1940."
    Psychiatry; Public health; Social medicine; United States; Belgium; Diaries; Medical education; France; Portugal; Medicine, Preventive; Chronic diseases; England; Endocrinology
  - Index, 1941; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 793, Box 182)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1941 diary
  - 1941, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 144 pages (Reel M Gre 3, Frame 798, Box 182)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg attends the National Research Council Committee on Medical Fellowships. The diary includes "Staff Conferences 18 February-11 December 1941."
    Child psychology; Diaries; Endocrinology; Medicine, Preventive; Chronic diseases; Public health; Psychiatry; United States; Social medicine; Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
  - Index, 1942; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 182, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 942)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1942 diary
  - 1942, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 159 pages (Box 182, Reel M Gre 3, Frame 947)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. The diary includes "Staff Conferences 7 January- 21 April 1942."
    Chronic diseases; Medicine, Preventive; Endocrinology; Public health; Psychiatry; Diaries; United States; Social medicine; Child psychology; Canada
  - Index, 1943; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 182, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 1)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1943 diary
    indexes (reference sources); Medical education
  - 1943, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 170 pages (Box 182, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 6)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. The Medical Sciences Division work is now related to the war. The diary also focuses on issues of health insurance, preventive and social medicine as well as the future of medicine in China.
    Public health; Social medicine; United States; World War II; Child psychology; Diaries; Chronic diseases; Endocrinology; Medicine, Preventive; Psychiatry
  - Index, 1944; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 182, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 176)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1944 diary
  - 1944, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 172 pages (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 181)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg travels around the United States and Canada to assess RF Medical Sciences programs. He attends Meeting of Committee on Medicine and Changing Order, AMA Committee on Post War Medical Services, and discusses RF interest in medical education in China.
    Diaries; Canada; World War II; Child psychology; United States; Social medicine; Public health; Psychiatry; Prevention and health; Medical education; Endocrinology; Chronic diseases
  - 1945, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 235 pages (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 353)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg travels to Europe to survey medical education, impact of war and need of RF support. He attends the NRC Meeting of the Committee on Research in Problems of Sex, IHD Meeting of Scientific Directors and Meeting of Committee on Medicine and the Changing Order.
    France; Ireland; Medical education; Prevention and health; Psychiatry; Public health; Diaries; World War II; Social medicine; United States; Child psychology; Sex; Czechoslovakia; Chronic diseases; Endocrinology; Europe; England; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956)
  - Index, 1946; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 588)
    d. 1957
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1946 diary.
  - 1946, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 232 pages (Reel M Gre 4, Frame 593, Box 183)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg travels to China to examine post war and civil war situation. Medical education and facilities of China are also assessed.
    Diaries; China; Canada; Sex; Public health; United States; Social medicine; Neurology; Medical education; Psychiatry; Physiology; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956); Peking Union Medical College
  - Index, 1947; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 827)
    A 6 page alphabetical index to the 1947 diary.
    Medical education; Diaries
  - 1947, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 161 pages (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 833)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg becomes the Chair of the Medical Committee of the Atomic Energy Committee and attends an AEC meeting of Advisory Council on Medicine and Biology.
    Diaries; Neurology; Medical education; Psychiatry; Physiology; Canada; Public health; Sex; Social medicine; United States; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956); Peking Union Medical College; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
  - Appendix, 1947; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 15 pages (Box 183, Reel M Gre 4, Frame 995)
    An RF Officer's conference is held to report on a recent trip to Germany to observe post war conditions and make recommendations for the possibility of a German RF program.
    Germany; United States
  - Index, 1948; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 183, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 1)
    A 7 page alphabetical index to the 1948 diary.
  - 1948, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 240 pages (Reel M Gre 5, Frame 8, Box 183)
    Scopea and Contents note
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg attends an AEC meeting of Advisory Council on Medicine and Biology.
    Dermatology; Denmark; England; Child psychology; United States; Psychiatry; Physiology; Netherlands; Medical education; Sweden; Diaries; Social medicine; Sex; Public health; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004); Peking Union Medical College; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956)
  - Index, 1949; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 183, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 248)
    A 6 page alphabetical index to the 1949 diary.
  - 1949, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 225 pages (Box 184, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 254)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg attends an AEC meeting of Advisory Council on Medicine and Biology, Meeting of the Neuropsychiatric Advisory Committee of the Veterans Administration, and Veterans Administration Sub-Committee on Clinical Psychology.
    Psychiatry; Physiology; United States; Scotland; Netherlands; Germany; Nursing; Neurology; Belgium; Endocrinology; Diaries; England; Austria; Peking Union Medical College; Rockefeller, Winthrop (1912-1973); Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004); Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956)
  - Appendix, 1949; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 12 pages (Reel M Gre 5, Frame 480, Box 184)
    Includes "Staff Conference Medical Sciences Division", :Meeting with Dr. L.H. Weed, Dr. Baird Hastings/and Dr. Homer Smith on NRC Fellowships", and "Notes on Meeting at Deauville"
    Medicine, Preventive; Medical sciences; Medical education; United States
  - Index, 1950; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Reel M Gre 5, Frame 493, Box 184)
    A 5 page alphabetical index to the 1950 diary.
  - 1950, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 167 pages (Box 184, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 498)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. The Medical Sciences Division is focused on teaching and research of psychiatry and its allied subjects. Gregg attends an AEC meeting of Advisory Council on Medicine and Biology. He travels to South America to survey medical education, nursing education and facilities. The diary includes "Appendix: Memorandum Relief, Rehabilitation and Development."
    Neurology; Nursing; Psychiatry; Public health; Switzerland; United States; Argentina; Medical education; France; Diaries; Brazil; Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978); Peking Union Medical College; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956); Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
  - 1950 October 29-December 29, Rockefeller Foundation; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 43 pages (Box 184, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 665)
    Gregg attends various meetings and conference including Conference on Psychiatric Education, APA; Meetings of the Association of American Medical Colleges; Milbank Memorial Fund Symposium on Biological Aspects of mental Health and Disease; VA Advisory Committee on Psychiatry and Neurology; American Association for the Advancement of Science.
  - Index, 1951; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 5, Frame 708, Box 184)
    A 8 page alphabetical index to the 1951 diary.
  - 1951, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles) (1894-1956); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; 201 pages (Reel M Gre 5, Frame 716, Box 184)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical sciences. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Gregg attends various meetings and conferences. He travels to India and Southeast Asia to survey medical education. Gregg is now the Vice-President of the Rockefeller Foundation.
    Diaries; United States; Switzerland; Public health; Psychiatry; Pakistan; Nursing; Neurology; Italy; Medical education; France; India; Bangladesh; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board
  - Index, 1952; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences (Box 184, Reel M Gre 5, Frame 918)
    A 7 page alphabetical index to the 1952 diary.